International

https://sputnikglobe.comprivacy\_policy

Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy

Sputnik International

Sputnik International is a global news media keeping you updated on all the latest world news 24/7. Browse Sputnik for breaking news and top stories on politics, economy, social media and the most viral trends.

2021-09-07T09:07+0000

2021-09-07T09:07+0000

2024-05-29T12:28+0000

https://cdn1.img.sputnikglobe.com/i/logo/logo-social.png

This Privacy Policy has been developed in accordance with the requirements of regulatory acts of the Russian Federation on personal data protection and in accordance with international law, including but not limited to Federal Law of the Russian Federation No. 152-FZ "On personal data" of July 27, 2006, and the GDPR regulations, specifically, "Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of the European Union of April 27, 2016, on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and on repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation)" or GDPR.We take timely measures to protect your personal data in compliance with this Privacy Policy (hereinafter the "Privacy Policy") and applicable law, and guarantee that your personal data is processed and protected to the highest global standards.Please read this Privacy Policy carefully, in order to understand the purposes for which we process your personal data as well as how you can exercise your rights regarding your personal data that is processed by the Agency.We tried to make this Privacy Policy as clear and simple as possible.This Privacy Policy shall be approved in its Russian version and translated into foreign languages, if necessary.If you have any questions regarding the processing or protection of your personal data, or any suggestions on how to improve this Privacy Policy, or if you would like to review the officially approved version, please send us a message using the contact information in Section 13 "Contacts".1. Scope of useThis Privacy Policy is designed to inform you about how we collect and process your personal data when you use our information resources (website, mobile app) and when we perform activity unrelated to the use of our information resources.This Privacy Policy applies to the processes specified in Section 5 "Privacy notice".Please note that our information resource (website, mobile app) may contain links to the resources of other service providers that are beyond our control and to whom this Privacy Policy does not apply.We require that our partners handle user data with care, therefore, we work only with companies that have established credibility.2. Categories of personal data subject to processingWe do not process your personal data when related to race, ethnicity, political views, religious or philosophical beliefs, health, sex life or biological characteristics that could make it possible to identify you.We do not intentionally collect your personal data from public sources unless otherwise stipulated by applicable law regulating the media.3. Categories of personal data subjectsPersonal data subjects include employees of the Agency and its representative offices, branches, bureaus, and users of the Agency’s websites, mobile apps and services; the Agency’s partners, customers, contractors and their representatives; journalists, bloggers (individuals promoting their personal websites, social media pages or content platforms), representatives of media outlets, participants in events held by the Agency, and other personal data subjects for the purpose of personal data processing. The objectives of personal data processing are set forth in Section 5 "Privacy notice".The Agency processes the personal data of adult individuals.4. Collecting personal data of underage usersOur information resources (website, mobile app) are not designed to process the personal data of underage individuals, unless it is stipulated by applicable law or permitted by the underage users’ parents or legal guardian.An underage user is an individual under the age of 18 unless otherwise stipulated by applicable law.If you have reasons to believe that that your child has provided us with his or her personal data, please let us know using the contact information in Section 13 "Contacts".5. Privacy notice5.1. Processing your personal data with identificationThe Agency’s information resources (website, mobile app) process personal data to identify you as an individual for the following purposes:5.1.1. Providing personal account features on the news websiteA news website is an online media outlet of the Agency specializing in collecting and releasing news content or news items.Purpose of personal data processingProviding users with the opportunity to participate in discussions on news and commentary.Personal data processed for this purposeYour name or username and email are necessary to create a personal account on the website.Once you have created an account, you can add more information to your personal account, including a profile photo, age, gender, date of birth, country, Google ID, Apple ID and social media accounts. This additional information is optional.If you provide your Google ID, Apple ID and social media ID, the website will process the data available on your social media accounts, including your first and last name, profile photo, date of birth, gender, email and subscription status.Legal grounds for processing your personal dataYour consent.Period of storage of your personal dataUntil you delete your account or withdraw your consent (or request that we delete your data).The withdrawal of consent procedure is described in Clause 8.7 "Right to withdraw consent".Transferring personal data to third partiesIf you provided your Google ID, Apple ID and social media ID via your personal account settings, your data will be transferred to third parties, specifically: Facebook Inc. (Facebook); Google LLC (Firebase, Google Analytics); Twitter Inc. (Twitter); Vkontakte LLC (Vkontakte) and Apple Inc.No data will be transferred to third parties if you do not provide your social media accounts via your personal account settings.Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizationsIf you provide your social media accounts via your personal account settings, your personal data will be processed in the Russian Federation, the United States and other countries where respective social media providers operate.If you do not provide your social media ID via your personal account settings, your personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.5.1.2. Providing a personal account on the media siteA media site is an Agency information resource that contains digital information products (photo, video, audio, etc.) created by the Agency for the purposes of further use and distribution.Purpose of personal data processingGranting licenses for the use of photo images, graphics, infographics and audiovisual content.Personal data processed for this purposeFirst name, last name, email, login, company name, company’s area of business, city, country, place of employment, job title, postal index, address, contact telephone number.Legal grounds for processing your personal dataA contract (license agreement).Period of storage of your personal dataUntil the contract (license agreement) expires.Upon expiration of the contract, the contract will be transferred to our internal archives. The contract will be stored for a period determined by internal file register regulations as required by applicable law.Transferring personal data to third partiesNo personal data is transferred to third parties.Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizationsYour personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.5.1.3. Providing a personal account to an organization on the commercial information sitePurpose of personal data processingProviding commercial services.Personal data processed for this purposeEmail, company name, login, information about newsfeed subscriptions.Legal grounds for processing your personal dataA contract (license agreement).Period of storage of your personal dataUntil the contract (license agreement) expires.Upon expiration of the contract, the contract will be transferred to our internal archives. The contract will be stored for a period determined by internal file register regulations as required by applicable law.Transferring personal data to third partiesNo personal data will be transferred to third parties.Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizationsYour personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.5.1.4. Organizing contests and other eventsPurpose of personal data processingOrganizing contests or campaigns for marketing purposes.Personal data processed for this purposeSocial media ID, first name, last name, patronymic (middle name), age, country, contacts for messengers and social media, contact telephone numbers, email, photos and videos.Legal grounds for processing your personal dataRules of participation for the contest or other event.Period of storage of your personal dataUntil the end of the event.Winners’ data are subject to processing until they receive their awards.Transferring personal data to third partiesIf third parties (partners, third-party platforms) are involved in organizing the event or presenting awards (postal services, courier services or partners), your personal data will be transferred to third parties.If no third parties are involved in organizing any stage of the contest, including presentation of awards to winners, the Agency will not transfer any personal data to third parties.Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizationsIf third parties (partners, third-party platforms) are involved in organizing an event or presenting an award (postal services, courier services or our partners), your personal data will be processed in the Russian Federation and in other countries where these third parties operate.If no third parties are involved, your personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.5.1.5. Sending email newsletters and notificationsPurpose of personal data processingDistributing newsletters.Personal data processed for this purposeFirst name, last name, email, your location (address), email client.Legal grounds for processing your personal dataYour consent.Period of storage of your personal dataUntil you withdraw your consent.The withdrawal of consent procedure is described in Clause 8.7 "Right to withdraw consent".Transferring personal data to third partiesThe Rocket Science Group (Mailchimp); SendPulse Inc. (Sendpulse).Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizationsYour personal data will be processed in the Russian Federation, the United States, Germany and Lithuania.5.1.6. Receiving and providing feedbackPurpose of personal data processingProcessing inquiries (complaints and suggestions) from individuals or representatives of organizations.Personal data processed for this purposeFirst name, last name; place of employment and job title; address; country; contact telephone numbers; email.Legal grounds for processing your personal dataEnsuring you receive feedback to resolve your issue.Period of storage of your personal dataUntil your issue is resolved.Transferring personal data to third partiesNo personal data is transferred to third parties.Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizationsYour personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.5.2. Personal data processing without your identificationOur website automatically collects data without identifying you as an individual for the following purposes:5.2.1. Analyzing the behavior of information resource (websites and mobile apps) users with internal analytics systemsPurpose of personal data processingImproving the operation of the website/mobile app, providing content, displaying the most relevant news items, displaying targeted advertising on the Agency’s website/mobile app and on advertising networks.Personal data processed for this purposeCookies, IP address, location, type and version of the device’s operating system, type and version of browser, type of device and screen resolution, source of traffic (website or ad), language of the operating system and browser, user’s online activity.Legal grounds for processing your personal dataLegitimate interest.When processing your data, we act based on our legitimate interest because no other grounds apply in this case. Our performance depends on your interest in the content we provide and on ease of use.User behaviour analysis on our website is a common practice among media outlets, therefore, we expect you to be aware of this. We assure you that any analysis of your data that we conduct to achieve the said goal will have no significant impact on your rights and freedoms.Period of storage of your personal dataThe period of storage depends on the type of cookie.For more information on cookie types, please refer to free third-party websites, for example: https://www.hotcleaner.com/cookie-editor/.Transferring personal data to third partiesNo personal data is transferred to third parties.Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizationsYour personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.5.2.2 Analyzing the behavior of information resource (websites and mobile apps) users with third-party resourcesPurpose of personal data processingImproving the operation of the website/mobile app, providing content, displaying the most relevant news items and displaying targeted advertising.Personal data processed for this purposeCookies, IP address, location, type and version of the device’s operating system, type and version of browser, type of device and the screen resolution, source of traffic (website or ad), language of the operating system and browser, user’s online activity.Legal grounds for processing your personal dataYour consent.Period of storage of your personal data1) until a cookie expires, which depends on its type. For more information on cookie types and their according lifetimes, please refer to free third-party websites, for example: https://www.hotcleaner.com/cookie-editor/.2) until you withdraw your consent (decline data processing).The withdrawal of consent procedure is described in Clause 8.7 "Right to withdraw consent".Transferring personal data to third partiesTo accomplish this purpose, we connect to information resources of third-party services.We provide these services the opportunity to gather your personal data for analysis. In this case, the processing of your personal data is subject to the privacy policies of these third-party services.Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizationsYour personal data will be processed in the Russian Federation, the United States, Egypt and other countries where the involved third-party services operate.5.3. Data processing for internal Agency purposes without using the information resourcesWe process your personal data without using the information resources for the following purposes:5.3.1. Accreditation of media representatives or bloggers for an Agency event or an event organized by the AgencyPurpose of personal data processingAccreditation of media representatives or bloggers for an Agency event or an event organized by the Agency.Personal data processed for this purposeFirst name, last name, patronymic (middle name); gender; citizenship; identification document data; photograph; copies of passport pages; place of employment and job title; visa category and number; email; contact telephone numbers; purpose of visit to the country.Legal grounds for processing your personal dataYour consent.Period of storage of your personal dataFor the period of accreditation and one year after the accreditation expires.Transferring personal data to third partiesYour personal data will be transferred to third parties if the Agency involves them in the event.Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizationsYour personal data will be processed in the Russian Federation and in the country where an event is held.5.3.2. Invitation to an Agency eventPurpose of personal data processingOrganizing an Agency event.Personal data processed for this purposeFirst name, last name, patronymic (middle name); photograph; place of employment and job title; email; contact telephone numbers; academic degree; profile; contact information for messengers and social media.Legal grounds for processing your personal dataYour consent.Period of storage of your personal dataUntil the end of the event.Transferring personal data to third partiesYour personal data will be transferred to third parties if the Agency uses them in organizing the event.Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizationsYour personal data will be processed in the Russian Federation and the country where the event is held.5.3.3. Processing the data of representatives of the Agency’s partners, contractors and clientsPurpose of personal data processingExecuting, performing and terminating a civil contract, approving a contract with a contractor.Personal data processed for this purposeFirst name, last name, patronymic (middle name); place of employment and job title; email; contact telephone number.Legal grounds for processing your personal dataActions towards executing a contract as well as performance of the contract (any type of contract).Period of storage of your personal dataUntil execution of the contract; until termination/expiration of the contract.Upon termination/expiration of the contract, the contract shall be transferred to the archives. The period of storage shall be determined by internal document management regulations in compliance with applicable law.Transferring personal data to third partiesNo personal data is transferred to third parties.Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizationsPersonal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.5.3.4. Content production by a media outletPurpose of personal data processingFor media outlet operations.Personal data processed for this purposeFirst name, last name, patronymic (middle name); place of employment and job title; photograph; audio recording of an interview; video recording of an interview or speech; profile; email; contact telephone number; contact information for messengers and social media.Legal grounds for processing your personal dataLegitimate interest.When gathering your data, we act based on our legitimate interest because no other grounds apply in this case. Our operation involves promptly responding to events in various areas of society and presenting them in the form of news content. When producing news content in the course of our operation as a media outlet, we may use personal data and these personal data will become publicly available unless it violates the rights and freedoms of an individual. We expect you to be aware of this.Period of storage of your personal dataIndefinitely, as part of our journalistic activity as a media outlet.Transferring personal data to third partiesNo personal data is transferred to third parties.Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizationsYour personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.5.3.5. Newsletters to representatives of media outletsPurpose of personal data processingDistributing newsletters.Personal data processed for this purposeFirst name, last name, patronymic (middle name); place of employment; contact telephone number; email; country.Legal grounds for processing your personal dataYour consent.Period of storage of your personal dataUntil you withdraw your consent.The withdrawal of consent procedure is described in Clause 8.7 "Right to withdraw consent".Transferring personal data to third partiesNo personal data is transferred to third parties.Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizationsYour personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.6. Automated individual decision-making and profilingTo accomplish the purposes for which we process your personal data, we do not engage in automated individual decision-making, including profiling.7. Destroying personal dataPersonal data will be destroyed upon achieving the purposes of processing it, upon expiration of the storage period, upon withdrawal of the subject’s consent to processing or upon termination of the contract unless otherwise specified by applicable law. Personal data is also subject to destruction if it is established that it was processed unlawfully.8. Your rights8.1. Right to access your personal informationYou have the right to obtain information from us about the processing of your personal data, the purpose of processing, categories, recipients or categories of recipients, including from other countries or international organizations, the period of storage, conditions of terminating the processing of your data and the source of your personal data.You have the right to request an electronic copy of your data that we process in electronic form, in a widely used format, if this right is explicitly granted by applicable law.8.2. Right to correct your personal dataIf your personal data is inaccurate, incomplete or outdated, you have the right to require that we correct it without delay on our part or, when appropriate, to correct it on your own, for example, in your personal account settings.You will be notified once we have corrected your personal data.8.3. Right to delete your personal dataYou have the right to request that we delete your personal data without delay on our part or, when appropriate, delete it yourself, for example, in your personal account settings.If we cannot delete your personal data, we will anonymize your personal data to make it impossible to identify the owner.You will be notified once we have deleted or anonymized your personal data.8.4. Right to restrict (block) processingYou have the right to request that we restrict (block) the processing of your personal data. You may exercise this right only in the following cases:1) you have disputed the accuracy of your personal data for a period that allowed us sufficient time to verify these data;2) processing your personal data is against the law and you object to your personal data being deleted and request that we restrict their use;3) we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of processing but you need them to impose, pursue or protect your legal requirements;4) you object to the processing until it is verified that our legitimate grounds override your grounds.If the processing of your personal data is restricted (blocked), we will suspend processing until the restriction is lifted but will continue to store your personal data.You can lift the restriction (block) from the processing of your personal data at any time by sending us a request using the methods specified in Section 13 "Contacts".8.5. Right to data portabilityYou have the right to obtain your personal data in a structured and computer-readable format as well as the right to have this data transferred to a different organization.You may exercise this right when your data is processed electronically based on your consent or a signed agreement to which you are a party or this right is explicitly granted by applicable law and is technically exercisable.8.6. Right to objectYou have the right to object to the processing of your personal data at any time based on a substantiated objection, when we process your data:1) to perform tasks in the public interest or to exercise official authority conferred on us;2) based on the legitimate interests that we or a third party pursue, except when pursuing these interests is necessary to protect your rights and freedoms.We will not process your personal data if we cannot demonstrate convincing legal grounds for processing them.You may, at any time, object to the processing of your personal data for marketing purposes, including for profiling, if such objection is explicitly stipulated by applicable law.8.7. Right to withdraw consentIf your personal data are processed on the grounds of your consent, you have the right to withdraw it. We use a simple 'withdrawal of consent' procedure:1) withdrawal of consent to email newsletters.You can withdraw your consent using any of the methods below:a) click "unsubscribe" in any distributed email;b) send us a withdrawal notice in a reply to an email newsletter;c) turn off email newsletters in your personal account settings, where available.2) withdrawal of consent to personal data processing via your account on the website.You can withdraw your consent using any of the methods below:a) delete your account in the settings of your personal account on the websites (you will find a link to delete your account in Settings);b) send us a withdrawal notice using the methods specified in Section 13 "Contacts".3) withdrawal of consent to cookie processing (declining cookie processing).You can withdraw consent (decline processing) by disabling the categories of your personal data subject to processing in the tracking settings on the website or using the guide in the Cookie and Automatic Logging Policy. Depending on the type of cookie files, they may be deleted automatically once you close the browser on your device. If automatic deletion is not applicable, the processing will cease upon your withdrawing consent.4) withdrawal of consent to personal data processing for purposes unrelated to the use of our information resources.You can withdraw your consent by sending us a notice using the methods specified in Section 13 "Contacts".8.8. Right to file a complaint with a supervisory authorityYou have the right to file a complaint with an authorized supervisory authority in your country if you have doubts about our methods for processing your data or protecting and enforcing your rights.If you are a citizen of the Russian Federation or reside on the territory of the Russian Federation, you will find the contacts of the supervisory authority on the website of the Federal Service for Supervision of Communications Information Technology and Mass Media (Roskomnadzor).If you are a citizen of the European Union or reside in the EU territory, you will find the contacts of the supervisory authority on the European Data Protection Board website.If you are a citizen or a resident of a non-EU country, you will find the contacts of the supervisory authority on the official website of this country’s competent authority.8.9. Request for additional information required to identify a data subjectIf the data you provided are insufficient for observing your rights, we may request additional data from you to verify your identity. We do our best to request only essential information that is absolutely necessary. If you fail to provide additional information, we will not be able to observe your rights. If you believe that we violate your rights by requesting additional information, you can file a complaint with a respective supervisory authority.8.10. Terms of providing information on your rightsWe provide information on observing your rights free of charge. If your request is clearly unsubstantiated or excessive (specifically, due to repetitiveness), we may refuse to respond or charge a fee for providing the requested information.8.11. Exercising your rightsWe provide several methods for exercising your rights:1) You can use the online feedback form available on the website to send us a request regarding your personal data protection;2) You can exercise your rights without assistance, when available, via your personal account;3) You can address critical issues directly to the person in charge of data protection using the method specified in Section 13 "Contacts".8.12. When we are restricted from observing your rightsWe may limit the scope of our obligations and restrict your rights when required by applicable law.These restrictions may apply if your personal data is processed:1) to protect national security;2) for protection;3) for public security;4) during a preliminary inspection, investigation, identity verification or the prosecution of criminal offences or the execution of criminal penalties, including the safeguarding against and the prevention of threats to public security;5) for other important objectives of legitimate general public interest for the state in which you are located, in particular an important economic or financial interest, including monetary, budgetary or taxation matters, public health or social security;6) for the protection of judicial independence and judicial proceedings;7) for the prevention, investigation, detection and prosecution of breaches of ethics for regulated professions;8) for a monitoring, inspection or regulatory function connected to the exercise of official authority;9) for the protection of the data subject or the rights and freedoms of others;10) for exercising the right to file civil law claims or enforce court judgements.There are also special conditions that must be met for your rights to be exercised, specifically:Exemptions from the right to delete personal data:1) observing the right to freedom of expression and freedom of information;2) performing a statutory obligation that requires the processing of personal data under applicable law or for accomplishing an objective of general public interest or for exercising official authority imposed on us by applicable law;3) protecting the public interest in the area of public health;4) processing for archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes;5) initiating, conducting or defending a legal claim.Exemptions from the right to restrict (block) processing:1) introducing, meeting or defending legal requirements, upon your consent;2) protecting the rights of another individual or a legal entity;3) for pursuing important legitimate public state interests.If we are not able to observe your rights upon your request, we will send you a substantiated refusal.9. Cookies and automatic loggingTo accomplish the purposes set forth in Clause 5.2 of this Privacy Policy, we use cookies and automatic logging.A cookie is a small data file stored on your device (computer, tablet, smart phone, etc.).Automatic logging is a log file used by our web servers and security systems.We process this data solely for the safe use of our website as well as to improve its performance.We do not use this data to identify you or integrate these data with other data. Nor do we transfer this data or create user profiles.You can learn more about how we use these technologies in our "Cookie and automatic logging policy".10. Guarantees regarding personal data transfer to third countriesIf we deal with a contractor whose country of operation is not on the list of countries ensuring an adequate level of personal data protection, we use standard contractual terms as recommended by the European Commission, the Federal Service for Supervision of Communications Information Technology and Mass Media (Roskomnadzor) and national law. We adopted security measures to protect your personal data according to the best security and privacy practices. We use safety precautions to protect your information.11. Data securityThe personal data we collect and store constitute classified information. They are protected from loss, manipulation or unauthorised access, by virtue of technical tools and organizational procedures. We continuously improve our data protection systems.We assess impacts on data protection in order to identify your risks during data processing. We minimize detected risks by employing technical and organisational security measures.You are responsible for the safekeeping of the password we provide for your personal account on our website. You must maintain this password in confidence and never transfer it to anybody.12. Policy amendmentsWe reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy from time to time.We will inform you of any changes to this Privacy Policy using all available means (via your contact email provided during registration or via our website during your next visit).Please review every update to this Privacy Policy.13. ContactsTo send us a message concerning the protection of personal data, please use the feedback form.You can address most critical questions on personal data protection directly to our data protection officer at the following email:First name: DmitryLast name: NaimushinEmail: privacy@sputniknews.comPlease note that this contact information may only be used for inquiries into personal data processing and protection. Unrelated inquiries will not be considered.For inquiries unrelated to personal data protection please use the email from the Agency’s contact list.Be sure to address your request to the appropriate department. If you send your request to the wrong department your issue may remain unresolved because departments only respond to requests within their competence.Last updated: 23.01.2023

Sputnik International

feedback@sputniknews.com

+74956456601

MIA „Rossiya Segodnya“

252

60

2021

Sputnik International

feedback@sputniknews.com

+74956456601

MIA „Rossiya Segodnya“

252

60

News

en\_EN

Sputnik International

feedback@sputniknews.com

+74956456601

MIA „Rossiya Segodnya“

252

60

Sputnik International

feedback@sputniknews.com

+74956456601

MIA „Rossiya Segodnya“

252

60

Sputnik International

Sputnik News, sputnik, Sputnik International, sputnik EN, sputnik US, sputnik GB, news, World News, international news, Breaking News, Top Stories, news in English, breaking news headlines, breaking news today, breaking news near me, news now world, breaking news now, top stories news, usa news today headlines

Sputnik News, sputnik, Sputnik International, sputnik EN, sputnik US, sputnik GB, news, World News, international news, Breaking News, Top Stories, news in English, breaking news headlines, breaking news today, breaking news near me, news now world, breaking news now, top stories news, usa news today headlines

Privacy Policy
==============

This Privacy Policy has been developed in accordance with the requirements of regulatory acts of the Russian Federation on personal data protection and in accordance with international law, including but not limited to Federal Law of the Russian Federation No. 152-FZ "On personal data" of July 27, 2006, and the GDPR regulations, specifically, "Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of the European Union of April 27, 2016, on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and on repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation)" or GDPR.

We take timely measures to protect your personal data in compliance with this Privacy Policy (hereinafter the "Privacy Policy") and applicable law, and guarantee that your personal data is processed and protected to the highest global standards.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully, in order to understand the purposes for which we process your personal data as well as how you can exercise your rights regarding your personal data that is processed by the Agency.

We tried to make this Privacy Policy as clear and simple as possible.

This Privacy Policy shall be approved in its Russian version and translated into foreign languages, if necessary.

If you have any questions regarding the processing or protection of your personal data, or any suggestions on how to improve this Privacy Policy, or if you would like to review the officially approved version, please send us a message using the contact information in Section 13 "[Contacts](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/privacy_policy.html#contacts)".

**1\. Scope of use**

This Privacy Policy is designed to inform you about how we collect and process your personal data when you use our information resources (website, mobile app) and when we perform activity unrelated to the use of our information resources.

This Privacy Policy applies to the processes specified in Section 5 "[Privacy notice](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/privacy_policy.html#privacy-notice)".

Please note that our information resource (website, mobile app) may contain links to the resources of other service providers that are beyond our control and to whom this Privacy Policy does not apply.

We require that our partners handle user data with care, therefore, we work only with companies that have established credibility.

**2\. Categories of personal data subject to processing**

We do not process your personal data when related to race, ethnicity, political views, religious or philosophical beliefs, health, sex life or biological characteristics that could make it possible to identify you.

We do not intentionally collect your personal data from public sources unless otherwise stipulated by applicable law regulating the media.

**3\. Categories of personal data subjects**

Personal data subjects include employees of the Agency and its representative offices, branches, bureaus, and users of the Agency’s websites, mobile apps and services; the Agency’s partners, customers, contractors and their representatives; journalists, bloggers (individuals promoting their personal websites, social media pages or content platforms), representatives of media outlets, participants in events held by the Agency, and other personal data subjects for the purpose of personal data processing. The objectives of personal data processing are set forth in Section 5 "[Privacy notice](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/privacy_policy.html#privacy-notice)".

The Agency processes the personal data of adult individuals.

**4\. Collecting personal data of underage users**

Our information resources (website, mobile app) are not designed to process the personal data of underage individuals, unless it is stipulated by applicable law or permitted by the underage users’ parents or legal guardian.

An underage user is an individual under the age of 18 unless otherwise stipulated by applicable law.

If you have reasons to believe that that your child has provided us with his or her personal data, please let us know using the contact information in Section 13 "[Contacts](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/privacy_policy.html#contacts)".

**5\. Privacy notice**

**5.1. Processing your personal data with identification**

The Agency’s information resources (website, mobile app) process personal data to identify you as an individual for the following purposes:

**5.1.1. Providing personal account features on the news website**

A news website is an online media outlet of the Agency specializing in collecting and releasing news content or news items.

**Purpose of personal data processing**

Providing users with the opportunity to participate in discussions on news and commentary.

**Personal data processed for this purpose**

Your name or username and email are necessary to create a personal account on the website.

Once you have created an account, you can add more information to your personal account, including a profile photo, age, gender, date of birth, country, Google ID, Apple ID and social media accounts. This additional information is optional.

If you provide your Google ID, Apple ID and social media ID, the website will process the data available on your social media accounts, including your first and last name, profile photo, date of birth, gender, email and subscription status.

**Legal grounds for processing your personal data**

Your consent.

**Period of storage of your personal data**

Until you delete your account or withdraw your consent (or request that we delete your data).

The withdrawal of consent procedure is described in Clause 8.7 "[Right to withdraw consent](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/privacy_policy.html#right-to-withdraw-consent)".

**Transferring personal data to third parties**

If you provided your Google ID, Apple ID and social media ID via your personal account settings, your data will be transferred to third parties, specifically: Facebook Inc. (Facebook); Google LLC (Firebase, Google Analytics); Twitter Inc. (Twitter); Vkontakte LLC (Vkontakte) and Apple Inc.

No data will be transferred to third parties if you do not provide your social media accounts via your personal account settings.

**Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizations**

If you provide your social media accounts via your personal account settings, your personal data will be processed in the Russian Federation, the United States and other countries where respective social media providers operate.

If you do not provide your social media ID via your personal account settings, your personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.

**5.1.2.** Providing a personal account on the [media site](https://sputnikmediabank.com/)

A media site is an Agency information resource that contains digital information products (photo, video, audio, etc.) created by the Agency for the purposes of further use and distribution.

**Purpose of personal data processing**

Granting licenses for the use of photo images, graphics, infographics and audiovisual content.

**Personal data processed for this purpose**

First name, last name, email, login, company name, company’s area of business, city, country, place of employment, job title, postal index, address, contact telephone number.

**Legal grounds for processing your personal data**

A contract (license agreement).

**Period of storage of your personal data**

Until the contract (license agreement) expires.

Upon expiration of the contract, the contract will be transferred to our internal archives. The contract will be stored for a period determined by internal file register regulations as required by applicable law.

**Transferring personal data to third parties**

No personal data is transferred to third parties.

**Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizations**

Your personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.

**5.1.3. Providing a personal account to an organization on the commercial information site**

**Purpose of personal data processing**

Providing commercial services.

**Personal data processed for this purpose**

Email, company name, login, information about newsfeed subscriptions.

**Legal grounds for processing your personal data**

A contract (license agreement).

**Period of storage of your personal data**

Until the contract (license agreement) expires.

Upon expiration of the contract, the contract will be transferred to our internal archives. The contract will be stored for a period determined by internal file register regulations as required by applicable law.

**Transferring personal data to third parties**

No personal data will be transferred to third parties.

**Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizations**

Your personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.

**5.1.4. Organizing contests and other events**

**Purpose of personal data processing**

Organizing contests or campaigns for marketing purposes.

**Personal data processed for this purpose**

Social media ID, first name, last name, patronymic (middle name), age, country, contacts for messengers and social media, contact telephone numbers, email, photos and videos.

**Legal grounds for processing your personal data**

Rules of participation for the contest or other event.

**Period of storage of your personal data**

Until the end of the event.

Winners’ data are subject to processing until they receive their awards.

**Transferring personal data to third parties**

If third parties (partners, third-party platforms) are involved in organizing the event or presenting awards (postal services, courier services or partners), your personal data will be transferred to third parties.

If no third parties are involved in organizing any stage of the contest, including presentation of awards to winners, the Agency will not transfer any personal data to third parties.

**Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizations**

If third parties (partners, third-party platforms) are involved in organizing an event or presenting an award (postal services, courier services or our partners), your personal data will be processed in the Russian Federation and in other countries where these third parties operate.

If no third parties are involved, your personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.

**5.1.5. Sending email newsletters and notifications**

**Purpose of personal data processing**

Distributing newsletters.

**Personal data processed for this purpose**

First name, last name, email, your location (address), email client.

**Legal grounds for processing your personal data**

Your consent.

**Period of storage of your personal data**

Until you withdraw your consent.

The withdrawal of consent procedure is described in Clause 8.7 "[Right to withdraw consent](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/privacy_policy.html#right-to-withdraw-consent)".

**Transferring personal data to third parties**

The Rocket Science Group (Mailchimp); SendPulse Inc. (Sendpulse).

**Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizations**

Your personal data will be processed in the Russian Federation, the United States, Germany and Lithuania.

**5.1.6. Receiving and providing feedback**

**Purpose of personal data processing**

Processing inquiries (complaints and suggestions) from individuals or representatives of organizations.

**Personal data processed for this purpose**

First name, last name; place of employment and job title; address; country; contact telephone numbers; email.

**Legal grounds for processing your personal data**

Ensuring you receive feedback to resolve your issue.

**Period of storage of your personal data**

Until your issue is resolved.

**Transferring personal data to third parties**

No personal data is transferred to third parties.

**Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizations**

Your personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.

**5.2. Personal data processing without your identification**

Our website automatically collects data without identifying you as an individual for the following purposes:

**5.2.1. Analyzing the behavior of information resource (websites and mobile apps) users with internal analytics systems**

**Purpose of personal data processing**

Improving the operation of the website/mobile app, providing content, displaying the most relevant news items, displaying targeted advertising on the Agency’s website/mobile app and on advertising networks.

**Personal data processed for this purpose**

Cookies, IP address, location, type and version of the device’s operating system, type and version of browser, type of device and screen resolution, source of traffic (website or ad), language of the operating system and browser, user’s online activity.

**Legal grounds for processing your personal data**

Legitimate interest.

When processing your data, we act based on our legitimate interest because no other grounds apply in this case. Our performance depends on your interest in the content we provide and on ease of use.

User behaviour analysis on our website is a common practice among media outlets, therefore, we expect you to be aware of this. We assure you that any analysis of your data that we conduct to achieve the said goal will have no significant impact on your rights and freedoms.

**Period of storage of your personal data**

The period of storage depends on the type of cookie.

For more information on cookie types, please refer to free third-party websites, for example: [https://www.hotcleaner.com/cookie-editor/](https://www.hotcleaner.com/cookie-editor/).

**Transferring personal data to third parties**

No personal data is transferred to third parties.

**Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizations**

Your personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.

**5.2.2 Analyzing the behavior of information resource (websites and mobile apps) users with third-party resources**

**Purpose of personal data processing**

Improving the operation of the website/mobile app, providing content, displaying the most relevant news items and displaying targeted advertising.

**Personal data processed for this purpose**

Cookies, IP address, location, type and version of the device’s operating system, type and version of browser, type of device and the screen resolution, source of traffic (website or ad), language of the operating system and browser, user’s online activity.

**Legal grounds for processing your personal data**

Your consent.

**Period of storage of your personal data**

1) until a cookie expires, which depends on its type. For more information on cookie types and their according lifetimes, please refer to free third-party websites, for example: [https://www.hotcleaner.com/cookie-editor/](https://www.hotcleaner.com/cookie-editor/).

2) until you withdraw your consent (decline data processing).

The withdrawal of consent procedure is described in Clause 8.7 "[Right to withdraw consent](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/privacy_policy.html#right-to-withdraw-consent)".

**Transferring personal data to third parties**

To accomplish this purpose, we connect to information resources of third-party services.

We provide these services the opportunity to gather your personal data for analysis. In this case, the processing of your personal data is subject to the privacy policies of these third-party services.

**Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizations**

Your personal data will be processed in the Russian Federation, the United States, Egypt and other countries where the involved third-party services operate.

**5.3. Data processing for internal Agency purposes without using the information resources**

We process your personal data without using the information resources for the following purposes:

**5.3.1. Accreditation of media representatives or bloggers for an Agency event or an event organized by the Agency**

**Purpose of personal data processing**

Accreditation of media representatives or bloggers for an Agency event or an event organized by the Agency.

**Personal data processed for this purpose**

First name, last name, patronymic (middle name); gender; citizenship; identification document data; photograph; copies of passport pages; place of employment and job title; visa category and number; email; contact telephone numbers; purpose of visit to the country.

**Legal grounds for processing your personal data**

Your consent.

**Period of storage of your personal data**

For the period of accreditation and one year after the accreditation expires.

**Transferring personal data to third parties**

Your personal data will be transferred to third parties if the Agency involves them in the event.

**Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizations**

Your personal data will be processed in the Russian Federation and in the country where an event is held.

**5.3.2. Invitation to an Agency event**

**Purpose of personal data processing**

Organizing an Agency event.

**Personal data processed for this purpose**

First name, last name, patronymic (middle name); photograph; place of employment and job title; email; contact telephone numbers; academic degree; profile; contact information for messengers and social media.

**Legal grounds for processing your personal data**

Your consent.

**Period of storage of your personal data**

Until the end of the event.

**Transferring personal data to third parties**

Your personal data will be transferred to third parties if the Agency uses them in organizing the event.

**Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizations**

Your personal data will be processed in the Russian Federation and the country where the event is held.

**5.3.3. Processing the data of representatives of the Agency’s partners, contractors and clients**

**Purpose of personal data processing**

Executing, performing and terminating a civil contract, approving a contract with a contractor.

**Personal data processed for this purpose**

First name, last name, patronymic (middle name); place of employment and job title; email; contact telephone number.

**Legal grounds for processing your personal data**

Actions towards executing a contract as well as performance of the contract (any type of contract).

**Period of storage of your personal data**

Until execution of the contract; until termination/expiration of the contract.

Upon termination/expiration of the contract, the contract shall be transferred to the archives. The period of storage shall be determined by internal document management regulations in compliance with applicable law.

**Transferring personal data to third parties**

No personal data is transferred to third parties.

**Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizations**

Personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.

**5.3.4. Content production by a media outlet**

**Purpose of personal data processing**

For media outlet operations.

**Personal data processed for this purpose**

First name, last name, patronymic (middle name); place of employment and job title; photograph; audio recording of an interview; video recording of an interview or speech; profile; email; contact telephone number; contact information for messengers and social media.

**Legal grounds for processing your personal data**

Legitimate interest.

When gathering your data, we act based on our legitimate interest because no other grounds apply in this case. Our operation involves promptly responding to events in various areas of society and presenting them in the form of news content. When producing news content in the course of our operation as a media outlet, we may use personal data and these personal data will become publicly available unless it violates the rights and freedoms of an individual. We expect you to be aware of this.

**Period of storage of your personal data**

Indefinitely, as part of our journalistic activity as a media outlet.

**Transferring personal data to third parties**

No personal data is transferred to third parties.

**Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizations**

Your personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.

**5.3.5. Newsletters to representatives of media outlets**

**Purpose of personal data processing**

Distributing newsletters.

**Personal data processed for this purpose**

First name, last name, patronymic (middle name); place of employment; contact telephone number; email; country.

**Legal grounds for processing your personal data**

Your consent.

**Period of storage of your personal data**

Until you withdraw your consent.

The withdrawal of consent procedure is described in Clause 8.7 "[Right to withdraw consent](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/privacy_policy.html#right-to-withdraw-consent)".

**Transferring personal data to third parties**

No personal data is transferred to third parties.

**Transferring personal data to third countries and international organizations**

Your personal data will be processed only in the Russian Federation.

**6\. Automated individual decision-making and profiling**

To accomplish the purposes for which we process your personal data, we do not engage in automated individual decision-making, including profiling.

**7\. Destroying personal data**

Personal data will be destroyed upon achieving the purposes of processing it, upon expiration of the storage period, upon withdrawal of the subject’s consent to processing or upon termination of the contract unless otherwise specified by applicable law. Personal data is also subject to destruction if it is established that it was processed unlawfully.

**8\. Your rights**

**8.1. Right to access your personal information**

You have the right to obtain information from us about the processing of your personal data, the purpose of processing, categories, recipients or categories of recipients, including from other countries or international organizations, the period of storage, conditions of terminating the processing of your data and the source of your personal data.

You have the right to request an electronic copy of your data that we process in electronic form, in a widely used format, if this right is explicitly granted by applicable law.

**8.2. Right to correct your personal data**

If your personal data is inaccurate, incomplete or outdated, you have the right to require that we correct it without delay on our part or, when appropriate, to correct it on your own, for example, in your personal account settings.

You will be notified once we have corrected your personal data.

**8.3. Right to delete your personal data**

You have the right to request that we delete your personal data without delay on our part or, when appropriate, delete it yourself, for example, in your personal account settings.

If we cannot delete your personal data, we will anonymize your personal data to make it impossible to identify the owner.

You will be notified once we have deleted or anonymized your personal data.

**8.4. Right to restrict (block) processing**

You have the right to request that we restrict (block) the processing of your personal data. You may exercise this right only in the following cases:

1) you have disputed the accuracy of your personal data for a period that allowed us sufficient time to verify these data;

2) processing your personal data is against the law and you object to your personal data being deleted and request that we restrict their use;

3) we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of processing but you need them to impose, pursue or protect your legal requirements;

4) you object to the processing until it is verified that our legitimate grounds override your grounds.

If the processing of your personal data is restricted (blocked), we will suspend processing until the restriction is lifted but will continue to store your personal data.

You can lift the restriction (block) from the processing of your personal data at any time by sending us a request using the methods specified in Section 13 "[Contacts](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/privacy_policy.html#contacts)".

**8.5. Right to data portability**

You have the right to obtain your personal data in a structured and computer-readable format as well as the right to have this data transferred to a different organization.

You may exercise this right when your data is processed electronically based on your consent or a signed agreement to which you are a party or this right is explicitly granted by applicable law and is technically exercisable.

**8.6. Right to object**

You have the right to object to the processing of your personal data at any time based on a substantiated objection, when we process your data:

1) to perform tasks in the public interest or to exercise official authority conferred on us;

2) based on the legitimate interests that we or a third party pursue, except when pursuing these interests is necessary to protect your rights and freedoms.

We will not process your personal data if we cannot demonstrate convincing legal grounds for processing them.

You may, at any time, object to the processing of your personal data for marketing purposes, including for profiling, if such objection is explicitly stipulated by applicable law.

**8.7. Right to withdraw consent**

If your personal data are processed on the grounds of your consent, you have the right to withdraw it. We use a simple 'withdrawal of consent' procedure:

1) withdrawal of consent to email newsletters.

You can withdraw your consent using any of the methods below:

a) click "unsubscribe" in any distributed email;

b) send us a withdrawal notice in a reply to an email newsletter;

c) turn off email newsletters in your personal account settings, where available.

2) withdrawal of consent to personal data processing via your account on the website.

You can withdraw your consent using any of the methods below:

a) delete your account in the settings of your personal account on the websites (you will find a link to delete your account in Settings);

b) send us a withdrawal notice using the methods specified in Section 13 "[Contacts](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/privacy_policy.html#contacts)".

3) withdrawal of consent to cookie processing (declining cookie processing).

You can withdraw consent (decline processing) by disabling the categories of your personal data subject to processing in the tracking settings on the website or using the guide in the [Cookie and Automatic Logging Policy](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/cookie.html). Depending on the type of cookie files, they may be deleted automatically once you close the browser on your device. If automatic deletion is not applicable, the processing will cease upon your withdrawing consent.

4) withdrawal of consent to personal data processing for purposes unrelated to the use of our information resources.

You can withdraw your consent by sending us a notice using the methods specified in Section 13 "[Contacts](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/privacy_policy.html#contacts)".

**8.8. Right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority**

You have the right to file a complaint with an authorized supervisory authority in your country if you have doubts about our methods for processing your data or protecting and enforcing your rights.

If you are a citizen of the Russian Federation or reside on the territory of the Russian Federation, you will find the contacts of the supervisory authority on the website of the Federal Service for Supervision of Communications Information Technology and Mass Media ([Roskomnadzor](https://rkn.gov.ru/)).

If you are a citizen of the European Union or reside in the EU territory, you will find the contacts of the supervisory authority on the [European Data Protection Board](https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members_en) website.

If you are a citizen or a resident of a non-EU country, you will find the contacts of the supervisory authority on the official website of this country’s competent authority.

**8.9. Request for additional information required to identify a data subject**

If the data you provided are insufficient for observing your rights, we may request additional data from you to verify your identity. We do our best to request only essential information that is absolutely necessary. If you fail to provide additional information, we will not be able to observe your rights. If you believe that we violate your rights by requesting additional information, you can file a complaint with a respective supervisory authority.

**8.10. Terms of providing information on your rights**

We provide information on observing your rights free of charge. If your request is clearly unsubstantiated or excessive (specifically, due to repetitiveness), we may refuse to respond or charge a fee for providing the requested information.

**8.11. Exercising your rights**

We provide several methods for exercising your rights:

1) You can use the [online feedback form](https://sputnikglobe.com/?modal=feedbackprivacy) available on the website to send us a request regarding your personal data protection;

2) You can exercise your rights without assistance, when available, via your personal account;

3) You can address critical issues directly to the person in charge of data protection using the method specified in Section 13 "[Contacts](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/privacy_policy.html#contacts)".

**8.12. When we are restricted from observing your rights**

We may limit the scope of our obligations and restrict your rights when required by applicable law.

These restrictions may apply if your personal data is processed:

1) to protect national security;

2) for protection;

3) for public security;

4) during a preliminary inspection, investigation, identity verification or the prosecution of criminal offences or the execution of criminal penalties, including the safeguarding against and the prevention of threats to public security;

5) for other important objectives of legitimate general public interest for the state in which you are located, in particular an important economic or financial interest, including monetary, budgetary or taxation matters, public health or social security;

6) for the protection of judicial independence and judicial proceedings;

7) for the prevention, investigation, detection and prosecution of breaches of ethics for regulated professions;

8) for a monitoring, inspection or regulatory function connected to the exercise of official authority;

9) for the protection of the data subject or the rights and freedoms of others;

10) for exercising the right to file civil law claims or enforce court judgements.

There are also special conditions that must be met for your rights to be exercised, specifically:

**Exemptions from the right to delete personal data:**

1) observing the right to freedom of expression and freedom of information;

2) performing a statutory obligation that requires the processing of personal data under applicable law or for accomplishing an objective of general public interest or for exercising official authority imposed on us by applicable law;

3) protecting the public interest in the area of public health;

4) processing for archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes;

5) initiating, conducting or defending a legal claim.

**Exemptions from the right to restrict (block) processing:**

1) introducing, meeting or defending legal requirements, upon your consent;

2) protecting the rights of another individual or a legal entity;

3) for pursuing important legitimate public state interests.

If we are not able to observe your rights upon your request, we will send you a substantiated refusal.

**9\. Cookies and automatic logging**

To accomplish the purposes set forth in [Clause 5.2](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/privacy_policy.html#without-identification) of this Privacy Policy, we use cookies and automatic logging.

A cookie is a small data file stored on your device (computer, tablet, smart phone, etc.).

Automatic logging is a log file used by our web servers and security systems.

We process this data solely for the safe use of our website as well as to improve its performance.

We do not use this data to identify you or integrate these data with other data. Nor do we transfer this data or create user profiles.

You can learn more about how we use these technologies in our "[Cookie and automatic logging policy](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/cookie.html)".

**10\. Guarantees regarding personal data transfer to third countries**

If we deal with a contractor whose country of operation is not on the list of countries ensuring an adequate level of personal data protection, we use standard contractual terms as recommended by the European Commission, the Federal Service for Supervision of Communications Information Technology and Mass Media ([Roskomnadzor](https://rkn.gov.ru/)) and national law. We adopted security measures to protect your personal data according to the best security and privacy practices. We use safety precautions to protect your information.

**11\. Data security**

The personal data we collect and store constitute classified information. They are protected from loss, manipulation or unauthorised access, by virtue of technical tools and organizational procedures. We continuously improve our data protection systems.

We assess impacts on data protection in order to identify your risks during data processing. We minimize detected risks by employing technical and organisational security measures.

You are responsible for the safekeeping of the password we provide for your personal account on our website. You must maintain this password in confidence and never transfer it to anybody.

**12\. Policy amendments**

We reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy from time to time.

We will inform you of any changes to this Privacy Policy using all available means (via your contact email provided during registration or via our website during your next visit).

Please review every update to this Privacy Policy.

**13\. Contacts**

To send us a message concerning the protection of personal data, please use the [feedback form](https://sputnikglobe.com/?modal=feedbackprivacy).

You can address most critical questions on personal data protection directly to our data protection officer at the following email:

First name: Dmitry

Last name: Naimushin

Email: [privacy@sputniknews.com](mailto:privacy@sputniknews.com)

Please note that this contact information may only be used for inquiries into personal data processing and protection. Unrelated inquiries will not be considered.

For inquiries unrelated to personal data protection please use the email from the Agency’s [contact list](https://sputnikglobe.com/docs/index.html).

Be sure to address your request to the appropriate department. If you send your request to the wrong department your issue may remain unresolved because departments only respond to requests within their competence.

Last updated: 23.01.2023

__International

* Contact Us
* Privacy Feedback
* Tracking preferences

© 2024 Sputnik All rights reserved. 18+

Newsfeed

0

Access to the chat has been blocked for violating the [rules](https://sputniknews.com/docs/comments.html) . You will be able to participate again through:∞. If you do not agree with the blocking, please use the [feedback form](https://sputniknews.com/?modal=feedback)

The discussion is closed. You can participate in the discussion within 24 hours after the publication of the article.

To participate in the discussion  
log in or register

loader

Chats

Заголовок открываемого материала
